We’ve all heard of IQ, and terms like EQ, which relates to your emotional intelligence, are commonly used.
我们都听说过智商，像EQ这类与情商相关的术语也被广泛使用。
But have you heard of AQ?
但你听说过逆商（AQ）吗？
AQ stands for adversity quotient and measures your ability to deal with the ups and downs of life.
逆商的全称是逆境商数，它衡量的是一个人应对人生起伏的能力。
Being able to handle these rough patches we all go through is not only important in our personal lives but in our professional lives too.
能否妥善处理这些我们都会经历的困境，不仅在个人生活中至关重要，在职业生涯里亦是如此。
So how can we learn to be more resilient?
那么，我们该如何学会让自己更具韧性呢？
Adverse situations can take us by surprise and shock us.
逆境往往来得猝不及防，让我们措手不及。
In the workplace, it could be in the form of redundancies, the company we work for going under or being restructured, or even missing out on a promotion.
职场中，逆境可能表现为被裁员、供职的公司倒闭或重组，甚至是错失晋升机会。
Failed friendships and relationships, financial hard times and even bereavements are things that can occur outside of work.
而职场之外，也可能遭遇友情破裂、感情失败、经济拮据乃至痛失亲友等变故。
AQ measures our ability to withstand the shocks when life throws curveballs at us – how likely we are to crumble or thrive in these situations.
逆商衡量的是，当生活向我们抛出难题时，我们承受冲击的能力——在这些处境下，我们是丢盔弃甲还是迎难而上。
It can be used to predict our attitudes, perseverance, longevity, and the way we learn from changes in environment.
它可以用来预测我们的态度、毅力、耐力，以及我们从环境变化中学习的方式。
In short, our resilience when there is a drastic change.
简而言之，逆商体现的是我们面对剧变时的韧性。
Luckily, there are some steps you can take to help you be more resilient and adaptable in the face of adversity, according to Dr Shahram Heshmat, professor of health economics at the University of Illinois.
伊利诺伊大学健康经济学教授沙赫拉姆·赫什马特博士表示，幸运的是，我们可以通过一些方法，让自己在逆境面前更具韧性和适应能力。
First, try and find a meaningful goal.
首先，树立一个有意义的目标。
Resilient people often have an aim and are able to concentrate more on a desired outcome, seeing negative situations as a bump in the road on the way to achieving their goal.
韧性强的人通常都有明确的目标，能够更专注于想要的结果，将困境视为实现目标路上的小坎坷。
Learning to relax and regulate your emotions is another key step – one way to help you destress is by practising breathing exercises.
其次，学会放松和调节情绪，呼吸练习就是一种缓解压力的有效方式。
Likewise, dwelling on things and letting them get to you can cause you to be stressed.
同样，一味纠结于烦心事、让负面情绪影响自己，会导致压力倍增。
See difficulties more as an opportunity to learn and grow emotionally.
不妨把困难看作是学习和心智成长的机会。
Finally, make sure you have a good social support network.
最后，建立良好的社交支持网络。
Being able to talk with someone about the challenges we face can help.
能向他人倾诉自己面临的挑战，本身就是一种帮助。
Things happen in life we can’t prevent – and sometimes they aren’t pleasant.
生活中总会发生一些我们无法预料的事——有时这些事并不令人愉快。
But, taking a few steps to be more resilient can make them a little easier to get through.
但只要采取一些方法提升韧性，我们就能更从容地度过这些难关。